Hello English learners and welcome to another great lesson with us here at EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you a great upper intermediate lesson.
今天我们为大家带来一堂很棒的中高级课程。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to talk about a topic that's been in the news recently and this topic is...
我们要讨论一个最近新闻里的话题，这个话题是……
The bird flu.
禽流感。
That's right.
没错。
So can you tell us what the bird flu really is?
那么你能告诉我们禽流感到底是什么吗？
Basically the story is a lot of chickens and birds keep getting this disease and they've
基本上，情况是很多鸡和鸟不断感染这种疾病，而且它们
managed to pass this disease to humans.
成功地将这种疾病传染给了人类。
And the fear is that humans will start to pass this disease to each other and a huge,
而人们担心的是，人类会开始互相传染，导致世界上
huge number of people in the world could get really sick.
大量人口患病。
Okay.
好的。
Yes.
是的。
So it sounds scary.
听起来很可怕。
Well, it may be a little bit scary, but we do have some interesting language.
嗯，可能有点吓人，但我们确实有一些有趣的语言点。
We've got language to talk about a disease and language that you might use in a planning
我们有谈论疾病的语言，也有你在工作规划会议上
meeting at work.
可能用到的语言。
All right.
好的。
So let's start by looking at our vocabulary preview for this dialogue.
那么我们先来看看这段对话的词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay.
好的。
The first word on our vocabulary preview today is contingency plan.
今天词汇预览的第一个词是应急计划。
Contingency plan.
应急计划。
So a contingency plan is a...
所以应急计划就是……
A plan that you make to prepare for an emergency.
你为应对紧急情况而制定的计划。
So like a backup plan.
就像后备计划。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Yep.
嗯。
Contingency plan.
应急计划。
And our last word for the vocabulary preview today is pandemic.
今天词汇预览的最后一个词是大流行病。
Pandemic.
大流行病。
So a pandemic is something scary.
所以大流行病是可怕的东西。
Well, yes.
嗯，是的。
It's an event where a disease affects a lot of people.
这是一种疾病影响很多人的事件。
Like we're talking millions of people.
比如我们说的是数百万人。
Okay.
好的。
And it spreads very quickly and it goes international.
而且它传播得非常快，并且跨越国界。
Okay.
好的。
So a disease that spreads very fast and goes everywhere.
所以是一种传播很快、无处不在的疾病。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Pandemic.
大流行病。
Okay.
好的。
So we're ready to listen to our dialogue.
那我们准备听对话吧。
We're going to be at a business meeting where people are talking about a contingency plan.
我们将参加一个商务会议，人们正在讨论应急计划。
Well, right.
嗯，对。
Let's move to our next order of business.
我们进入下一个议题。
As many of you are aware, in recent weeks there has been a lot of media coverage surrounding
正如各位所知，最近几周媒体大量报道了
this bird flu issue.
禽流感问题。
And it's come to my attention that our company lacks any sort of bird flu contingency plan.
我注意到我们公司缺乏任何禽流感应急计划。
Basically, we need to come up with a clear plan.
基本上，我们需要制定一个明确的计划。
We need to outline specific actions that our company can take to maintain critical business
我们需要列出公司可以采取的具体行动，以维持关键业务
functions in case a pandemic strikes.
功能，以防大流行病爆发。
So what I'd like to do is first appoint someone to look after drafting our plan.
所以我想先指定一个人负责起草我们的计划。
Ralph, I'd like you to head up this project.
拉尔夫，我希望你来负责这个项目。
Sure.
当然。
No problem.
没问题。
What issues do you want me to consider?
您希望我考虑哪些问题？
Well, let's see.
嗯，让我想想。
There are a few points we need to be thinking about.
有几个要点我们需要考虑。
First, I'll need you to analyse our numbers and figure out what kind of financial impact
首先，我需要你分析我们的数据，弄清楚疫情可能带来的
an outbreak might have.
财务影响。
You'll also need to think about how we can avoid any of our employees getting infected.
你还需要考虑如何避免我们的员工被感染。
Think of ways to reduce employee-customer contact.
想办法减少员工与客户的接触。
Perhaps some IT solutions that will allow our people to work from home.
也许一些IT解决方案能让员工在家办公。
I guess you'll need me to forecast employee absences as well, right?
我想你还需要我预测员工缺勤情况，对吧？
And I'll think about the impact this will have on our clients.
我会考虑这对客户的影响。
Hey, what about vaccines?
嘿，疫苗呢？
Should we be thinking about getting vaccines for our employees?
我们是否应该考虑为员工接种疫苗？
Exactly right.
完全正确。
So I'll leave this to you and we'll review the draft plan in two weeks.
所以我把这事交给你，我们两周后审阅计划草案。
Okay.
好的。
Does anyone want to order some KFC for lunch?
有人想点肯德基当午餐吗？
Alright what an ironic meeting.
好吧，真是讽刺的相遇。
They are talking about the bird flu and they are going to have chicken.
他们正在谈论禽流感，却要吃鸡肉。
Yes, after sneezing all over.
是啊，打完喷嚏之后。
Yeah, I guess now we could take a look at our language takeaway for this dialogue.
嗯，我想现在我们可以看看这段对话的语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
We heard a lot of really useful language in this dialogue and right now we're going to
我们在对话中听到了很多有用的语言，现在我们要
look at four different words from the dialogue.
看看对话中的四个不同的单词。
The first one is critical.
第一个是 critical。
Critical.
Critical。
We've got some examples of this word that will help us to understand the meaning.
我们有一些这个词的例子，可以帮助我们理解它的意思。
So let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
It's absolutely critical that we increase our sales.
增加销售额是绝对关键的。
If not, the company will go bankrupt.
否则，公司就会破产。
Example two.
例子二。
We have a critical shortage of food.
我们严重短缺食物。
If we don't get help, people will die.
如果得不到帮助，人们就会死亡。
Example three.
例子三。
This is a critical step in the process.
这是过程中关键的一步。
You can't make a mistake here.
你在这里不能犯错。
So when something's critical, it's basically really important, really urgent.
所以当某件事是 critical 时，基本上就是非常重要、非常紧急。
Right.
对。
Okay, great word.
好的，很好的词。
Critical.
Critical。
The next word we have is outbreak.
下一个词是 outbreak。
Outbreak.
Outbreak。
An outbreak.
So an outbreak is a sudden start of a disease, right?
所以 outbreak 是指疾病的突然爆发，对吧？
Can I say, oh, I got an outbreak of flu.
我可以说“我爆发了流感”吗？
Can outbreak describe one person?
outbreak 能描述一个人吗？
No, an outbreak means that it's infecting a lot of people.
不，outbreak 意味着它感染了很多人。
Okay.
好的。
Not only one person.
不只是一个人。
So that we could say there was an outbreak of the flu at the office.
所以我们可以说办公室爆发了流感。
Right.
对。
Which there was.
确实爆发了。
Yeah.
是的。
A lot of people got sick here with the flu.
这里很多人得了流感。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好的。
Why don't you tell us about our third word?
不如你给我们讲讲第三个词？
Our third word is forecast.
第三个词是 forecast。
Forecast.
Forecast。
So to forecast basically means to predict.
所以 forecast 基本上就是预测的意思。
Exactly.
没错。
For example, you talk about the weather forecast.
比如，你会说天气预报。
Yep.
嗯。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
And the last word for our language takeaway is vaccines.
我们语言摘录的最后一个词是 vaccines。
Vaccines.
Vaccines。
So vaccines are something we all had when we were children.
疫苗是我们小时候都打过的东西。
That's true.
没错。
They are injections that you get to prevent you from getting sick later.
它们是注射剂，用来预防以后生病。
Right.
对。
So an injection of medicine from your doctor so that you don't get a disease in the future.
就是医生给你打一针药，这样你将来就不会得某种疾病。
Right.
对。
When we are small, we get polio vaccine.
我们小时候会打小儿麻痹症疫苗。
Yeah.
嗯。
Or measles vaccine.
或者麻疹疫苗。
Measles.
麻疹。
Yeah.
嗯。
A lot of common diseases.
很多常见疾病。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So that's all for language takeaway.
语言摘录部分就到这里。
Some great language related to health and disease.
一些与健康和疾病相关的很棒的语言。
But we also heard some great business related words in this dialogue.
但我们在对话中也听到了一些很好的商务相关词汇。
That's true.
没错。
There's a lot of words that you can use in a planning meeting.
有很多词可以在计划会议上使用。
So let's look at those now in Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看看流利度构建中的那些词。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
In today's Fluency Builder, we're going to look at four useful phrases.
在今天的流利度构建中，我们将学习四个有用的短语。
Now this first phrase you can use when you want to change the subject at a meeting.
第一个短语可以在你想在会议上转换话题时使用。
Let's listen to what they said in the dialogue.
我们来听听他们在对话中说了什么。
Let's move to our next order of business.
我们进入下一个议题吧。
Okay.
好的。
So let's move to our next order of business.
那么，我们进入下一个议题。
It's a great way of saying let's move on.
这是表达“我们继续”的好方法。
Exactly.
没错。
Let's pass to the next topic.
我们转到下一个话题。
Great.
很好。
Speaking of passing to the next topic, we heard another really interesting phrase in
说到转到下一个话题，我们还听到了另一个非常有趣的短语，
the dialogue.
在对话中。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
We need to come up with a clear plan.
我们需要想出一个清晰的计划。
We need to think of a clear plan.
We need to come up with.
我们需要想出。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Our third phrase we heard in the dialogue is this.
我们在对话中听到的第三个短语是这个。
Okay.
好的。
I'd like you to head up this project.
我希望你来负责这个项目。
So this phrase head up.
所以这个短语“head up”。
This is a great phrase.
这是一个很棒的短语。
It means I'd like you to lead or take care of this project.
它的意思是“我希望你来领导或负责这个项目”。
Okay.
好的。
And the last phrase for fluency builder you can use when you want to give someone the
流畅表达中的最后一个短语，当你想把某项工作的责任交给某人时可以使用。
responsibility of a job.
我们听到了这个。
We heard this.
所以我把这个交给你了。
So I'll leave this to you.
This is you take charge.
这就是你负责。
Exactly.
没错。
I'll leave this to you.
我把这个交给你了。
So great way of delegating a responsibility.
所以这是委派责任的好方法。
And so we're going to leave you to listen to our dialogue a last time and be sure to
那么，我们让你最后再听一遍对话，一定要记住我们刚刚讨论的所有精彩词汇。
pick up all the great vocabulary that we just talked about.
好的。
Well right.
嗯，对。
Let's move to our next order of business.
我们进入下一个议题吧。
As many of you are aware in recent weeks there has been a lot of media coverage surrounding
正如你们许多人知道的，最近几周媒体对禽流感问题有很多报道。
this bird flu issue.
And it's come to my attention that our company lacks any sort of bird flu contingency plan.
我注意到我们公司缺乏任何应对禽流感的应急计划。
Basically we need to come up with a clear plan.
基本上我们需要制定一个明确的计划。
We need to outline specific actions that our company can take to maintain critical business
我们需要列出公司可以采取的具体行动，以维持关键业务
functions in case a pandemic strikes.
功能，以防疫情爆发。
So what I'd like to do is first appoint someone to look after drafting our plan.
所以我想做的是先指定一个人来负责起草我们的计划。
Ralph I'd like you to head up this project.
拉尔夫，我希望你来负责这个项目。
Sure no problem.
没问题。
What issues do you want me to consider.
你希望我考虑哪些问题？
Well let's see.
嗯，让我想想。
There are a few points we need to be thinking about.
有几个要点我们需要考虑。
First I'll need you to analyze our numbers and figure out what kind of financial impact
首先，我需要你分析我们的数据，弄清楚疫情可能带来的
an outbreak might have.
财务影响。
You also need to think about how we can avoid any of our employees getting infected.
你还需要考虑如何避免我们的员工被感染。
Think of ways to reduce employee customer contact.
想办法减少员工与客户的接触。
Perhaps some IT solutions that will allow our people to work from home.
也许可以借助一些IT解决方案，让员工在家办公。
I guess you'll need me to forecast employee absences as well right.
我想你还需要我预测员工的缺勤情况，对吧？
And I'll think about the impact this will have on our clients.
而且我会考虑这对我们的客户会产生什么影响。
Hey what about vaccines.
嘿，那疫苗呢？
Should we be thinking about getting vaccines for our employees.
我们是否应该考虑为员工接种疫苗？
Exactly right.
完全正确。
So I'll leave this to you and well we'll review the draft plan in two weeks.
所以我把这个交给你，我们两周后审阅计划草案。
Okay.
好的。
Does anyone want to order some KFC for lunch.
有人午餐想点肯德基吗？
Okay great.
好的，太好了。
So this contingency plan idea is really interesting right.
所以这个应急计划的想法真的很有趣，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
It makes sense for a company to prepare in case there is an outbreak of bird flu.
公司为禽流感爆发做准备是有道理的。
I mean they need to maintain their critical business functions even if all the employees
我的意思是，即使所有员工都生病了，他们也需要维持
are sick.
关键业务功能。
Hey right.
嘿，没错。
I guess that's really important and you have to forecast all these possibilities like people
我想这真的很重要，你必须预测所有可能性，比如员工
are going to be away from the office or even forecast less sales etc.
会缺勤，甚至预测销售额下降等。
That's right.
没错。
The interesting thing is that businesses that may not actually be involved in food production
有趣的是，那些实际上不涉及食品生产
or raising chickens or something like that are making these contingency plans.
或养鸡之类的企业也在制定这些应急计划。
I find that really fascinating.
我觉得这非常吸引人。
So it seems there is a lot of fear out there about the possibility of a pandemic.
所以看来人们对疫情爆发的可能性有很多担忧。
Yeah.
是的。
We're going to come out with a vaccine so we don't have to worry about these things.
我们会推出疫苗，所以我们不必担心这些事情。
That's true.
没错。
But until then we'll have to create contingency plans.
但在此之前，我们得制定应急计划。
That's right.
对。
Okay guys we're out of time today and I hope you enjoyed our lesson and found all these
好了各位，今天时间到了，希望你们喜欢这节课，并觉得这些
words and phrases really useful and you can apply them in real life.
单词和短语非常实用，能在实际生活中运用。
All right guys thanks for listening and be sure to check out our website EnglishPod.com
好了，感谢收听，记得访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com
where you can leave all your questions and comments.
在那里你可以留下所有问题和评论。
Marco and I are always around to answer your questions.
我和 Marco 随时都在，会回答你们的问题。
So until then it's bye.
那么，下次再见。
Goodbye.
再见。